Carbon removal is crucial for fighting climate change.
清除碳对于应对气候变化至关重要。
Scientists at Salk Institute are making use of the natural capacity of plants to absorb carbon dioxide by enhancing their root systems.
索尔克研究所的科学家正在利用植物吸收二氧化碳的天然能力，通过增强它们的根系来达到目的。
This optimization aims to increase the amount of carbon stored and extend the duration of its storage.
这种优化旨在增加碳的储存量，并延长其储存时间。
To design these climate-saving plants, the scientists are using a research tool called SLEAP — an AI software that tracks multiple features of root growth.
为了设计这些能拯救气候的植物，科学家们正在使用一种名为 SLEAP 的研究工具——这是一款能追踪根系生长多种特征的人工智能软件。
Created by Salk Fellow Talmo Pereira, SLEAP was initially designed to track animal movement in the lab.
SLEAP 由索尔克研究员塔尔莫·佩雷拉开发，最初是为了在实验室里追踪动物的运动。
Now, Pereira has teamed up with plant scientist Professor Wolfgang Busch to apply SLEAP to plants.
现在，佩雷拉与植物学家沃尔夫冈·布施教授合作，把 SLEAP 应用到植物上。
In a study published in Plant Phenomics, Busch and Pereira establish a new procedure for using SLEAP to analyze plant root phenotypes — how deep and wide they grow, how massive their root systems become, and other physical qualities.
在发表于《植物表型组学》的一项研究中，布施和佩雷拉建立了一套用 SLEAP 分析植物根系表型的新流程——包括根长得多深多宽、根系变得多庞大，以及其他物理特性。
Prior to SLEAP, tracking the physical characteristics of both plants and animals required a lot of labor that slowed the scientific process.
在有 SLEAP 之前，追踪植物和动物的物理特征需要大量人力，拖慢了科学研究的进程。
SLEAP uses computer vision (the ability for computers to understand images) and deep learning (an AI approach for training a computer to learn and work like the human brain) to help researchers process images much more quickly.
SLEAP 利用计算机视觉（计算机理解图像的能力）和深度学习（一种训练计算机像人脑一样学习和工作的人工智能方法），帮助研究人员更快地处理图像。
The application of SLEAP to plants has already enabled researchers to establish the most extensive catalog of plant root phenotypes to date.
将 SLEAP 应用于植物，已经让研究人员建立起迄今为止最全面的植物根系表型目录。
What’s more, tracking these physical root system characteristics helps scientists find genes associated with those characteristics, as well as whether multiple root characteristics are determined by the same genes or independently.
此外，追踪这些根系的物理特征，还能帮助科学家找到与这些特征相关的基因，并弄清多种根系特征是由相同的基因决定，还是各自独立决定的。
This allows the Salk team to determine what genes are most beneficial to their plant designs.
这使索尔克团队能够确定，哪些基因对他们的植物设计最有益。
“Our cooperation is truly proof of what makes Salk science so special and impactful,” says Pereira.
“我们的合作恰恰证明了是什么让索尔克的科学如此特别、如此有影响力，”佩雷拉说。
“We’re not just ‘borrowing’ from different disciplines — we’re really putting them on equal footing in order to create something greater than the sum of its parts.”
“我们不只是从不同学科‘借用’东西——我们真正让它们处于平等地位，以创造出大于各部分之和的成果。”